<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/shablona/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/shablona/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-17T17:02:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shablona/</id><title type="html">Open Source and Reproducible MIR Research</title><subtitle>The goal of this tutorial is to provide hands-on,  practical training for MIR researchers to learn modern tools  for improving the quality of their research software.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Part 1: Installing Tools</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/16/part-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Part 1:  Installing Tools" /><published>2018-08-16T15:16:46-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-16T15:16:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/16/part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/16/part-1.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome!  This part of the tutorial will cover installing the tools that you’ll need to have on your laptop:  the Python programming language, the Conda package manager, and the git version control system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-python&quot;&gt;Install Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the main &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Python page&lt;/a&gt;, and download Python 3.6 or higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mac users, you very probably have Python 2.7 on your computer – please do go and get Python 3.6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux users, you have some version of Python on your machine – please make sure that you have Python 3.6, and go and get it if not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows users, we &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; recommend that you install the [Windows System for Linux][wsl-install] and Ubuntu.  You can then do the rest of this tutorial as a Linux user!
While you’re welcome to use Powershell, we can’t guarantee that we’ll be able to help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;checkpoint&quot;&gt;Checkpoint&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;python &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Python 3.6.5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(You’ll see these checkpoints throughout the tutorial.  If you’re doing the tutorial with us in person, we’ll stop at these points to make sure that everyone is in the same place.  If your checkpoint is working, you can put a blue sticky note on your laptop.  If something’s not working, that’s totally OK!  Put a red sticky note on your machine, and we’ll come help.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-conda&quot;&gt;Install Conda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conda is a package manager for Python code and lower-level code that supports Python.
Anaconda is a version of Conda that comes with lots and lots of pre-installed packages for scientific computing.
We’re going to use Anaconda so we don’t have to go digging for obscure Fortran and C libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.anaconda.com/anaconda/install/&quot;&gt;Anaconda website&lt;/a&gt;, and follow the steps for your platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows users, please use your Linux install, and install the Linux version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gotchas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; or another non-bash shell, you’ll need to add things to your PATH yourself.  We recommend moving the lines that the installer added from your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; file to your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re using a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;virtualenv&lt;/code&gt;, you’ll need to turn it off before installing Anaconda!  Conda in general does not play well with virtualenvs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;checkpoint-1&quot;&gt;Checkpoint&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;conda &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;conda 4.5.10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-git&quot;&gt;Install git&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git is a version control system – it keeps track of changes that you make to your code.
This makes it hard for you to lose changes that you have made, and makes it easy for you to return to a working version of your code.
git in particular also makes it easy to collaborate with other folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/downloads&quot;&gt;git website&lt;/a&gt;, and follow the steps for your platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux users, you may already have git installed - please make sure that you’re on version 2.15 or or higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows users, please use your Linux install, and install the Linux version!  (We’ll stop reminding you about this soon, we promise.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend against using a graphical interface for git – mostly because we won’t be able to help you with it in this tutorial!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;checkpoint-2&quot;&gt;Checkpoint&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;git &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;git version 2.7.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success&quot;&gt;Success!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve installed everything we’ll need on our machines.  In &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfee.github.io/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/15/part-2.html&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;, we’ll set up the various web apps and accounts that we’ll need.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Welcome! This part of the tutorial will cover installing the tools that you’ll need to have on your laptop: the Python programming language, the Conda package manager, and the git version control system.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Part 2: Setting Up Services</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/15/part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Part 2:  Setting Up Services" /><published>2018-08-15T15:16:46-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-15T15:16:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/15/part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/15/part-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 2!  In this section we’ll set up accounts for the web services that we need – GitHub, Travis CI, and ReadTheDocs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-github&quot;&gt;Set Up GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub hosts your code, makes it easy for other folks to collaborate with you, and makes it easier for other web services to hook into your code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vist &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and create an account.  Once you’ve got an account, you need to create some SSH keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSH keys are big numbers that GitHub uses for authorization.  Setting them up can be a bit fincky, but we’ll get through it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, create a new SSH key by &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/generating-a-new-ssh-key-and-adding-it-to-the-ssh-agent&quot;&gt;following these steps&lt;/a&gt; – make sure to pick the correct platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we’ll add the key to our GitHub account.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/adding-a-new-ssh-key-to-your-github-account&quot;&gt;The steps to do so are here&lt;/a&gt; – again, make sure you pick the correct platform!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let’s [test our key out][github-shh-3]!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;checkpoint&quot;&gt;Checkpoint&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;ssh &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-T&lt;/span&gt; git@github.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;Hi &amp;lt;your-username&amp;gt;! You&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'ve successfully authenticated, but GitHub does not provide shell access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-travis-ci&quot;&gt;Set Up Travis CI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis CI is a tool for “Continuous Integration”, which is just a fancy word for running the code that tests your software whenever you change your software.
We won’t get to using Travis for a little bit, but let’s get the setup out of the way now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org&quot;&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt;, and make an account by pressing the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sign In With GitHub&lt;/code&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be asked to authorize Travis to use your Github account.  Do so, and you’ll get redirected to your profile screen.  On your profile screen, press the “Activate” button to finish connecting Travis to you GitHub code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be taken to a GitHub page - just press “Approve &amp;amp; Install”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;checkpoint-1&quot;&gt;Checkpoint&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No command line here - you should be able to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org&quot;&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt;, and see your name in the upper-right to indicate that you’re logged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-readthedocs&quot;&gt;Set Up ReadTheDocs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ReadTheDocs hosts your documentation, so that people know how to use your software!  We’ll get to ReadTheDocs nearer to the end of the tutorial, but let’s get things set up now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org&quot;&gt;ReadTheDocs&lt;/a&gt;, and press &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sign up&lt;/code&gt;, and the select &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sign Up With GitHub&lt;/code&gt;.  Like with Travis, you’ll be asked to authorize ReadTheDocs to use your GitHub account – do the same as you did before.
ReadTheDocs will also ask you to confirm your email, so open up your email client and do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;checkpoint-2&quot;&gt;Checkpoint&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No command line here either - you should be able to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org&quot;&gt;ReadTheDocs&lt;/a&gt; and see your GitHub username in the upper-right to indicate that you’re logged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success&quot;&gt;Success!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve set up the various web services we’ll need!  Next is &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfee.github.io/shablona/tutorial/2018/08/14/part-3.html&quot;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt;, where we’ll get to the code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-note-about-the-internet&quot;&gt;A Note About The Internet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the services we’ve go over are on the internet.  There are local tools that can do the same sorts of things that out of the scope of this tutorial.
If you need to keep you code secret, they might be right for you.  In general, we recommend using web services like the above because they’re much less hassle to set up.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to Part 2! In this section we’ll set up accounts for the web services that we need – GitHub, Travis CI, and ReadTheDocs.</summary></entry></feed>